This is me, practicing English with GPT-Live.
I do this every morning.
And every morning, I hit this exact wall.
The phrase I need is almost there.
But it won't come out.
If I stop to check my phone, the conversation dies.
If I just move on, the phrase I couldn't say is gone forever.
The best learning moment of my day evaporates.
Every single day.
So I built a coach that lives right here, in my field of view.
This is LinguaLens, on Even G2 smart glasses.
The moment I stumble, LinguaLens hears it and hands me one to three complete phrases I can say right now, with a gloss in my own language.
I pick one.
I say it.
The conversation never stops.
When GPT-Live uses a word I don't know, a three-word gloss.
That's all.
And in the quiet moments, the phrase I couldn't say comes back as a review card.
It shows up again tomorrow.
The freeze becomes the lesson.
Most of the time, it shows nothing.
A good coach knows when to stay quiet.
Why glasses?
A phone kills the conversation.
Audio would talk over it.
A silent HUD is the only interface that fits inside a conversation.
Every line of this app was written by Codex.
I directed, Codex coded.
The session logs are in the repo.
GPT-5.6 generates the review phrases.
Its fastest sibling, luna, makes the stay-quiet-or-help call in real time.
And the whole thing runs on a Bluetooth link so thin it forces honesty: text first, one image, nothing wasted.
You can try the full pipeline in two minutes, no glasses, no API key: the official simulator plays a scripted conversation, with the whole coaching loop live.
When the GPT-Live API opens, LinguaLens becomes its visual half.
GPT-Live does the talking.
LinguaLens does the catching.
LinguaLens. Full phrases when you're stuck. Silence when you're not.